/* Created and coded by Abhilash Narayan */
/* Quiz source: w3schools.com */
var quiz = {
    "JS": [
    {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is AI security primarily concerned with?  ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a":"Increasing the speed of AI models ",
    "b": "Protecting AI systems from threats and vulnerabilities ",
    "c": "Developing new AI technologies",
    "d": "Reducing the cost of AI implementation "
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Protecting AI systems from threats and vulnerabilities ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What is the primary goal of critical infrastructure cybersecurity?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To improve user experience",
    "b": "To ensure essential services remain operational and secure ",
    "c": "To reduce costs in the energy sector ",
    "d": "To promote technological innovation  ",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To ensure essential services remain operational and secure ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": " What is the primary goal of network security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To increase network speed",
    "b": " To protect a network and its data from unauthorized access and misuse ",
    "c": "To reduce the cost of network maintenance ",
    "d": "To enhance user experience  ",
    }
    ],
    "answer": " To protect a network and its data from unauthorized access and misuse ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": " What types of threats does endpoint security aim to prevent?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Malware and unauthorized access",
    "b": "High electricity consumption",
    "c": "Network speed reduction",
    "d": " Hardware malfunctions",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Malware and unauthorized access",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which of the following is a common practice in application security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Ignoring software updates",
    "b": "Code reviews",
    "c": "Removing encryption",
    "d": "Disabling firewalls",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Code reviews",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "What are the primary goals of cloud security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Reducing hardware costs and increasing storage capacity",
    "b": "Ensuring data privacy, integrity, and availability  ",
    "c": "Enhancing software performance and user experience ",
    "d": "Improving user interface design and accessibility",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Ensuring data privacy, integrity, and availability  ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What does information security (InfoSec) primarily aim to protect against?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction",
    "b": "Network speed and bandwidth issues",
    "c": "Hardware malfunctions and software bugs",
    "d": "User interface design and usability ",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following threats is NOT specifically mentioned as a concern for mobile security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Malware  ",
    "b": "Unauthorized access ",
    "c": "Data breaches",
    "d": "Hardware failures",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Hardware failures",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a key concern of AI security in the paragraph? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Ensuring data privacy ",
    "b": "Preventing model manipulation",
    "c": "Improving AI system efficiency ",
    "d": "Protecting against adversarial attacks "
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Improving AI system efficiency ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a focus area in critical infrastructure cybersecurity? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Managing risks",
    "b": "Responding to incidents ",
    "c": "Ensuring resilience ",
    "d": "Developing new software applications",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Ensuring resilience ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a measure included in network security? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Firewalls ",
    "b": "Encryption ",
    "c": "Cloud computing",
    "d": "Intrusion detection systems",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Cloud computing",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT typically included in endpoint security solutions?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Antivirus software",
    "b": "Firewalls",
    "c": "Encryption",
    "d": "Social media monitoring ",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Social media monitoring ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a measure in application security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Code reviews",
    "b": "Penetration testing",
    "c": "Secure coding practices",
    "d": "Software development lifecycle management",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Software development lifecycle management",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT mentioned as a key aspect of cloud security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Data encryption ",
    "b": "Identity and access management",
    "c": "Network security",
     "d": "Software development ",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Software development ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 15,
    "question": " Which of the following is NOT a measure mentioned as part of InfoSec?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Access control ",
    "b": "Encryption  ",
    "c": "Threat detection ",
    "d": "Marketing strategies",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Threat detection ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Which practice is NOT listed as a measure to enhance mobile security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Using strong passwords ",
    "b": "Enabling encryption",
    "c": "Regularly updating software",
    "d": "Increasing battery life",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Increasing battery life",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Why is AI security important according to the paragraph? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To ensure AI systems operate safely and ethically",
    "b": "To make AI systems more user-friendly",
    "c": "To enhance the speed of AI processing",
    "d": "To reduce the energy consumption of AI models",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To ensure AI systems operate safely and ethically",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Why is collaboration between government and private sectors important in critical infrastructure cybersecurity? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To create new regulations",
    "b": "To ensure compliance with security regulations ",
    "c": "To manage financial investments",
    "d": "To enhance customer service ",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To ensure compliance with security regulations ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "What are the three key aspects of network security mentioned in the paragraph?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Speed, scalability, and flexibility",
    "b": "Integrity, confidentiality, and availability ",
    "c": "Integrity, confidentiality, and availability ",
    "d": "Cost-efficiency, ease of use, and reliability",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Integrity, confidentiality, and availability ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of endpoint security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To increase network speed",
    "b": "To protect devices that connect to a network from threats",
    "c": "To monitor internet usage",
    "d": "To reduce software update frequency",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To protect devices that connect to a network from threats",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "What is the goal of implementing application security measures?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To reduce software costs",
    "b": "To enhance user experience",
    "c": "To ensure the application is secure from attacks and unauthorized access",
    "d": "To increase software download rates",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To ensure the application is secure from attacks and unauthorized access",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "What are the key aspects that InfoSec focuses on preserving?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Data backup and recovery ",
    "b": "Confidentiality, integrity, and availability",
    "c": "System performance and scalability",
    "d": "User convenience and interface",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Confidentiality, integrity, and availability",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Why is cloud security important for businesses?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To ensure faster internet speeds ",
    "b": "To safeguard sensitive information and maintain trust",
    "c": "To reduce the cost of cloud services ",
    "d": "To improve customer service ",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To safeguard sensitive information and maintain trust",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "What is the primary goal of mobile security?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To enhance app performance",
    "b": "To protect personal and corporate data on mobile devices",
    "c": "To improve device aesthetics",
    "d": "To speed up internet connectivity",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To protect personal and corporate data on mobile devices",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    // {
    // "id": 25,
    // "question": "Is JavaScript case-sensitive?",
    // "options": [
    // {
    // "a": "No",
    // "b": "Yes"
    // }
    // ],
    // "answer": "Yes",
    // "score": 0,
    // "status": ""
    // }
    ]
    }
    var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = cque;
    if (this.currentque < totalque) {
    $("#tque").html(totalque);
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
    $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
    $("#question-options").html("");
    for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
                    $("#question-options").append(
                    "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
                    "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
                    "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
                    quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
                    "</span></label>"
                    );
                }
            }
        }
    if (this.currentque <= 0) {
        $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
    }
    if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
        $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
    for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
        this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
    }
            return this.showResult(this.score);
        }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
        $("#result").addClass('result');
        $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
    for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
        var res;
    if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
        res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
    } else {
        res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
    }
        $("#result").append(
    '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
    '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
    '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
    '</div>'
    );
    }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
    var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
    option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
    option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
    option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
    if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
    }
    } else {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
    }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
    this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
    }
    var jsq = new quizApp();
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
    //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
    $(this).prop("checked", true);
    selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });